sfmoma.org 2015-06-26

# The San Francisco Museum of Modern Art (SFMOMA) | About Us | About Us | About the Site | SFMOMA Privacy Policy

* * *

The San Francisco Museum of Modern Art (" **SFMOMA** ") values the privacy of our users, members, and others who visit and use www.sfmoma.org and its associated websites and services (collectively, the " **SFMOMA Website** ") (collectively or individually "Users"). This privacy policy (the " **Privacy Policy** ") governs information you provide to us or that we learn from your use of the SFMOMA Website and tells you how we may collect, use, and in some instances share this information.

### The Information SFMOMA Collects

**User Provided Information:** You may provide to SFMOMA what is generally called "personally identifiable" information (such as your name, postal mailing address, email address, personal/business/mobile telephone number, billing information, and resume/CV) when you register on the SFMOMA Website or through services such as onsite touch-screen kiosks. In addition, SFMOMA may give you the option to provide us with certain demographic and preference information about yourself.

**"Cookies" Information:  ** When you visit the SFMOMA Website, we may send one or more cookies — a small text file containing a string of alphanumeric characters — to your computer.  The use of cookies is common practice and SFMOMA may use both session cookies and persistent cookies.  A persistent cookie remains after you close your browser and may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the SFMOMA Website. These persistent types of cookies can be removed.  Each web browser implements different functionality, so please refer to the manuals or technical support resources that are available in conjunction with your web browser to learn the correct way to modify your cookies set-up.  Please note that disabling cookies may prevent you from accessing some of the resources and functionality available via the SFMOMA Website. 

**"Automatically Collected" Information** : When you visit the SFMOMA Website or open one of our emails, we may use different types of technology to record certain information from your web browser.  This "automatically collected" information may include your Internet Protocol address ("IP Address"), web browser type, the web pages or sites that you visit just before or just after the SFMOMA Website, the pages you view on our website, and the dates and times that you visit. 

### The Way SFMOMA Uses Information

SFMOMA uses the information that we collect to provide various features and services to our Users, members, and visitors.

SFMOMA may use all of the information that we collect from our Users to understand usage trends and preferences, to improve the way the SFMOMA Website and SFMOMA apps work and look, to improve our promotional efforts, membership drives, and fundraising efforts, and to create new features and functionality.

SFMOMA may use automatically collected information and cookies information to: (a) remember your information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the SFMOMA Website; (b) provide custom, personalized content and information; (c) monitor the effectiveness of our promotional efforts, membership drives, and fundraising efforts; and (d) monitor aggregate usage metrics such as total number of visitors and pages viewed.

SFMOMA will use information you provide through the SFMOMA Website, such as your email address or other personally identifiable information: (a) without further consent, for non-promotional or administrative purposes such as notifying you of major website updates, and (b) to send promotional, fundraising, and membership-related communications to you unless you opt-out of receiving such communications.

You may request that SFMOMA delete your personal information by contacting us as directed below.

### When SFMOMA Discloses Information

SFMOMA may disclose both personally identifiable and automatically collected information to third party businesses, organizations, or persons to process such information on our behalf, to provide website maintenance and security, to provide various features and services to our Users, members, and visitors (including without limitation to enable sending of promotional, fundraising, and membership-related communications), to assist us in improving the way the SFMOMA Website works and looks, and to create new features.

We may share automatically collected and other aggregate non-personally-identifiable information with interested third parties to assist them in understanding the usage patterns for certain content, services, promotions, and/or functionality on the SFMOMA Website. 

Except as otherwise noted in this Privacy Policy, SFMOMA does not share personal information about Users with third parties unless doing so is appropriate to carry out a User’s request, or unless it reasonably believes that doing so is legally required or in SFMOMA's interest in order to protect its property and other legal rights or the property and rights of others.

We do not share personally identifiable information with third-party organizations for their marketing or promotional use: (a) unless we obtain your prior consent, or (b) as part of specific programs or features for which you will have the ability to opt-out.  By way of example, and without limitation, one such program may include sharing your information with [other Bay Area cultural organizations](http://www.theatrebayarea.org/?page=AudienceDatabase) through list exchanges designed to pair patrons with organizations whose work might interest them.

Please see the section entitled “Third Party Service Providers” below which addresses collection and use of your information by third parties (rather than by SFMOMA) to whom you may be redirected from the SFMOMA Website.

You may request that SFMOMA delete your personal information by contacting us as directed below.

### Third Party Service Providers

The SFMOMA Website may contain links to other websites, products, or services that SFMOMA does not own or operate.  For example, we may partner with third party service providers to provide our Users with certain functionality or features (e.g. [Museumtix](http://www.mtn.museumtix.com/) for online ticket sales).  At times, websites hosted by these third party service providers, or other partners, may appear as if you are still on the SFMOMA Website.  To tell whether you are on the SFMOMA Website or viewing third-party content, simply check the address of the page in your browser's address window.

We encourage you to read the privacy statements of each and every third-party website and service before providing any personally identifiable information to its operators.  Some of these third parties may share or sell the information that they collect from you.  SFMOMA is not responsible for the privacy practices of third parties.  If you choose to visit or use any third-party products, websites, or services, including those offered by our third party service providers or other partners, please be aware that this Privacy Policy will not apply to your activities or any information you disclose while using third-party products or services or otherwise interacting with any third parties.

### Your User Profile and Password for Your SFMOMA Online Account

Your SFMOMA online account allows you to access, update, and correct your personal information and email preferences at any time.  You may also request that SFMOMA delete your personal information by contacting us as directed below.

To protect your privacy and security, we take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access to your user profile. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information at all times.

### Your Postings

PLEASE NOTE THAT ANY INFORMATION THAT YOU POST FOR VIEWING ON THE SFMOMA WEBSITE IS MADE PUBLICLY AVAILABLE TO ALL USERS OF THE SFMOMA SITE.

### Children

SFMOMA does not collect personally identifiable information from children except in connection with certain features and programs which are identified on the SFMOMA Website as collecting such information.  Personally identifiable information collected from children by SFMOMA: (i) is not disclosed to third parties, (ii) is only used for the purposes of providing the applicable feature or program, and (iii) is not retained longer than necessary to provide the applicable feature or program.  If you have any questions or concerns, please contact us at [privacy@sfmoma.org](mailto:privacy@sfmoma.org?subject=SFMOMA%20Privacy%20Policy%20Inquiry).

### Our Commitment to Data Security

No data transmissions over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.  Consequently, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us and you do so at your own risk.  Once we receive your transmission, we make reasonable efforts to ensure security on our systems.  We employ encryption and firewalls to protect your information from unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction via the Internet.  However, please note that this is not a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of such firewalls and secure server software.

If SFMOMA learns of a security systems breach, then we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps.  By using the SFMOMA Website or providing personal information to us, you agree that we can communicate with you electronically regarding security, privacy, and administrative issues relating to your use of the SFMOMA Website.  SFMOMA may post a notice on the SFMOMA Website if a security breach occurs.  SFMOMA may also send an email to you at the email address you have provided to us in these circumstances.

### Special Note to International Users

The SFMOMA Website is hosted in the United States. If you are a User accessing the SFMOMA Website from the European Union, Asia, or any other region with laws or regulations governing personal data collection, use, and disclosure, that differ from United States laws, please note that you are transferring your personal data to the United States which does not have the same data protection laws as the EU and other regions, and by providing your personal data you consent to:

  * the use of your personal data for the uses identified above in accordance with the Privacy Policy;  
and
  * the transfer of your personal data to the United States as indicated above.

### Changes and Updates to This Privacy Policy

We may occasionally update this Privacy Policy. When we do, we will also revise the "Last Updated" section below. For changes to this Privacy Policy that may be materially less restrictive on our use or disclosure of personal information that you have provided to us, we will attempt to obtain your consent before implementing the change.  We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Policy to stay informed about how we are protecting the personal information we collect.  Your continued use of the SFMOMA Website constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Policy and any updates.

### Contacting SFMOMA

If you have any questions, comments, or concerns about this Privacy Policy, please email us at [privacy@sfmoma.org](mailto:privacy@sfmoma.org?subject=SFMOMA%20Privacy%20Policy%20Inquiry).

Last Updated July 19, 2010
